so this is very exciting confluence
starting to occur between the emerging
spaces of functional medicine and better
diagnostic medicine longevity medicine
and life extension biohacking and
quantified self technologies and citizen
science better science in all of the AH
mcc's and various fields of bioscience
neuroscience and the bioinformatics
capacities and the systems biology
capacities to integrate all of that to
really understand complex human bio
psycho system dynamics better all of
these systems having exponential curves
and all starting to have a confluence to
develop a new emerging field of human
wellbeing optimization
six principles of neurotic collective
scientific and philosophical to
well-being optimization first principle
is that we are focused on well-being
optimization rather than a disease model
or illness state were focused on how to
support more and more human flourishing
and increased human capacity and
resilience across all the physiologic
and psychologic dimensions they're
important to focus on a whole system's
and complex systems approach rather than
a reductive approach where we look at
individual pathways in isolation of each
other and look for single molecule
solutions or looking at the relationship
between all the pathways within primary
systems like neurotransmitters within a
nervous system and between systems like
the relationship between the brain and
the gut and so we can support all those
systems together whole systems and
complex systems three we'll focused on
increasing the regulatory capacity of
the whole system so increasing system
resilience and the robustness of its
capacity rather than just affecting
system states so rather than try to get
a biometric into the right level we want
to understand how the system regulates
the biometrics on its own and how we
support those regulatory systems so the
person becomes lastingly more adaptive
and more resilient independent of
ongoing utilization of the technologies
that we've developed for mind brain
interface we believe that the body
affects the mind and that the mind
affects the body and we can create
positive virtuous cycles between those
who are interested in developing
technologies that are physiologic
technologies that support cognitive and
psychological well-being and
psychological and cognitive technologies
that support physiologic well-being and
specifically synergies between those
that create virtuous cycles five we are
technology agnostic we're interested in
comprehensive attea across the space of
every kind of neural technology and
wellness technology that actually works
that's actually effective safe and
meaningful and then how to integrate all
those who are interested in transcranial
stimulation biochemical technologies and
microbiome ik technologies etc and
specifically how to be able to integrate
multiple kinds of
categories for optimized solutions for
people and lastly six-hour we integrate
all of that towards progressively more
and more personalization so that we can
adapt solutions to individual needs and
individual proclivities those are the
foundational kind of approaches of how
we work on well-being science and
optimization